The ghost with the most is back.
Beetlejuice Beetlejuice is a comedy, fantasy,
horror film directed by Tim Burton.
After a family tragedy, three generations of the Deetz
family return home to Winter River.
Still haunted by Betelgeuse, Lydia's life is turned upside down when her teenage
daughter, Astrid, accidentally opens the portal to the Afterlife.
Beetlejuice, played by Michael Keaton.
Lydia, played by Winona Ryder.
Delia, played by Catherine O'Hara.
Astrid, played by Jenna Ortega.
Rory, played by Justin Theroux.
Jackson, played by Willem Dafoe.
Beetlejuice is a 1988 American gothic horror comedy film directed by Tim Burton from a screenplay by
Michael McDowell and Warren Skaaren based on a story by McDowell and Larry Wilson.
The film stars Michael Keaton as Betelgeuse, along with Alec Baldwin, Geena
Davis, Jeffrey Jones, Catherine O'Hara and Winona Ryder.
The plot revolves around Adam and Barbara Maitland, a recently deceased couple.
As ghosts, they are not allowed to leave their house.
They contact Betelgeuse, a sleazy "bio-exorcist", to
scare the house's new inhabitants away.
The film prominently features music from Harry
Belafonte's albums Calypso and Jump Up Calypso.
Beetlejuice was released in the United States on March 30, 1988, by Warner Bros.
The film was a critical and commercial success, grossing
$84 million against a $15 million budget.
It won the Academy Award for Best Makeup and three Saturn Awards: Best Horror
Film, Best Makeup, and Best Supporting Actress for Sylvia Sidney.
The film's success spawned a media franchise, consisting of an animated television series,
video games, a 2018 stage musical, and a 2024 sequel, Beetlejuice Beetlejuice.
The film explores themes of afterlife, haunted
house, sequel, paranormal, teenage girl.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.